University Theses and Dissertations Collection UA098
Tufts Archival Research Center
- Oversize University Theses and Dissertations, 1932 -- 1988; UA098.003; 0.5 Linear Feet; 9 Volumes
  - Thesis 983, 1963; UA098.003.010 (Box 10)
    Age of color in art; important aspects and use of color from Impressionism to present, with related technical study in painting.
  - Theses 905, 1576, and unnumbered theses, 1961 -- 1985; UA098.003.011 (Box 11)
    - Sonata in E flat for Piano, 1961; UA098.003.011.00001 (Box 11)
      By Sara Collier.
    - Rhapsody for Violin and Orchestra, 1969; UA069.003.011.00002 (Box 11)
      By George William Huneke.
    - Computer Printout Accompanying Plan of Study Thesis No. 52, 1974; UA069.003.011.00003 (Box 11)
      Open for research
      By Richard F. Corn.
    - Odysseus: A Plan of Study Thesis Combining Ancient Greek Mythos and Musical Composition, 1985; UA069.003.011.00004 (Box 11)
      By Clifford Jay Turner. Includes audiotapes, libretto, and scores.
- School of Nutrition Theses, 1966 -- 1980; 1972 -- 1975; UA098.004; 1.2 Linear Feet
  These theses do not appear to have been bound and submitted to the Tufts libraries. They are not assigned numbers and are listed at the item level. They reflect work towards a Masters in Education in Nutrition in the Frances Stern Nutrition Center.
  - Development of the Surplus Food Programs in the United States compared with the Uses of Surplus Food in Canada and Opinions of some recipients of these foods from the Direct Distribution Program, 1966; UA098.004.001.00001; Whissell, Lorraine (Box 1)
    School of Nutrition Science and Policy
  - Developing Nutrition Education Materials for the Urban Child, 1969; UA098.004.001.00002; Gottlieb, Donna Dubin (Box 1)
  - The development of a tool to evaluate knowledge that patients with diabetes have in regard to insulin and diet, 1969; UA098.004.001.00003; Maher, Barbara (Box 1)
  - An investigation of some preliminary steps involved in coordinating the further developing community nutrition services: Applied to a specific area of the State of Maine, 1971; UA098.004.001.00004; Wardwell, Jane A. (Box 1)
  - A comprehensive nutrition education program for senior citizens, 1972; UA098.004.001.00005; Brizendine, Grace E. (Box 1)
  - A study of the use of behavior modification in treatment of obesity in several institutionalized emotionally disturbed boys with implications for general use, 1972; UA098.004.001.00006; Crossley, Janice (Box 1)
  - A study of the supplemental food program, 1972; UA098.004.001.00007; Epstein, Barbara L. (Box 1)
  - An experiment in integrating nutrition into the science curriculum of a group of people working for their high school equivalency diplomas, 1972; UA098.004.001.00008; Healy, Judith G. (Box 1)
  - An experiment in group nutrition-dental health education, 1972; UA098.004.001.00009; Kowal, Linda S. (Box 1)
  - The development of a nutrition instructional kit and a nutritional care program for Tufts-New England Medical Center Prenatal Clinic, 1972; UA098.004.001.00010; Pearson, Paula (Box 1)
  - A group approach to weight control based upon nutrition education and individualized diets, 1973; UA098.004.001.00011; Andry, Brenda Kaye (Box 1)
  - Analyzing, evaluating and developing guidelines for the metabolic research unit affiliation of the Frances Stern Nutrition Center Coordinated Dietetic Internship/Master's Degree Program, 1973; UA098.004.001.00012; Burton, Clarice Jean (Box 1)
  - The development and implementation of values clarification workshops for undergraduates in allied health professions, 1973; UA098.004.001.00013; Crocker, Ruth W. (Box 1)
  - Nutrition education for fourth year medical students, post-doctoral fellows, and physicians in diabetes clinic, 1973; UA098.004.001.00014; Thunberg, Barbara J. (Box 1)
  - A study of the food stamp population, 1975; UA098.004.001.00015; Callahan, Elizabeth A. (Box 1)
  - Compliance: A study of correlates of appointment compliance among obese nutrition clinic patients, 1975; UA098.004.001.00016; Shibata, Ellen (Box 1)
  - Development of dietary methodology as applied to the study of pre-school age children on a vegetarian diet, 1975; UA098.004.001.00017; Stenzler, Helene (Box 1)
  - Health related behaviors of vegetarians, natural and health food users, 1975; UA098.004.001.00018; Zabitz, Barabara P. (Box 1)
  - Development of a food record and method of its analysis for use with behavior modification group for weight reduction, 1976; UA098.004.001.00019; Yoder, Beulah H. (Box 1)
  - The influence of a vegetarian diet on milk lipid concentration: A study of American macrobiotic women, 1977; UA098.004.001.00020; Sondel, Sherie Ann (Box 1)
  - Nutritional knowledge, attitudes and practices of community health nurses in Portland, Maine, 1978; UA098.004.001.00021; Phillips, Peggy E. (Box 1)
  - Can macrobiotic diets for children ages six months through six years meet the recommended dietary allowances?, 1980; UA098.004.001.00022; Wright, Peggy Ann (Box 1)
- Theses containing A/V or electronic media, UA098.005; 3 Audiovisual Object(s)
  This series contains either A/V and electronic media material of a particular bound theses or theses consisting solely of A/V or electronic media. The bound volumes are still listed under series 2. To facilitate finding these kinds of theses, a separate series was created.
  This series is arranged as found.
  - Thesis 3633 accompanying material (1 of 2): a video cassette (VHS), UA098.005.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Thesis 3633 consists of two volumes and is accompanied by a video cassette (VHS) and a sound cassette which are stored separately in 39090015524628n and 39090015524636n. For bound volumes, see series 2.
    videocassette
  - Thesis 3633 accompanying material (2 of 2): a sound cassette, UA098.005.002.00001 (Box 2)
    Thesis 3633 consists of two volumes and is accompanied by a video cassette (VHS) and a sound cassette which are stored separately in 39090015524628n and 39090015524636n. For bound volumes see series 2.
    audiocassette
  - Thesis 2252 accompanying material: 1 sound cassette, UA098.005.002.00002 (Box 2)
    Internal notes
    Thesis 2252 is accompanied by 1 sound cassette; the 5 videoreels (Sony V-30H) that were part of the thesis are missing. For bound volume see series 2.
  - Thesis 780 accompanying material: a magnetic sound motion picture, UA098.005.003.00001 (Box 3)
    Thesis # 780 is accompanied by a magnetic sound motion picture. For bound volume see series 2.
  - Theses 5782, 6189, 6496, 6680, 6717, 2000 -- 2005; UA069.005.004 (Box 440)
    These theses include accompanying CDs in interior pockets.
  - Thesis 735 accompanying material: 3 compact discs and 1 DVD-R, 2006; UA098.005.005 (Box 5)
    These audiovisual materials were *not* accompanied by a bound text.
  - Thesis 6082 accompanying material: 1 compact disc, 2002; UA098.005.006 (Box 6)
  - The Changing Faces of Drum and Dance in Senegal—Jembe and Sabar Repertoire in Traditional and Contemporary Contexts, from Dakar to Boston, MA thesis supplementary DVD, 2008; UA098.000626; Ross, Alisha; 1 Audiovisual Object(s) (Box 7)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Transferred by Tisch Library, May 2022, UA-2023-040.
    Bound volume not held by Tufts; access via ProQuest.
- Deaccessioned theses, 1997 -- 2000; 1999 -- 2000; UA098.006; 0.25 Linear Feet
  This series contains forms submitted by students for the appoval of their thesis or dissertation. Between 1997 and 2000 the physical works were destroyed after being microfilmed or having a digital copy created.
  This series is not arranged.
  - Approval of thesis/dissertation forms, 1997 -- 2000; UA098.006.001.00001 (Box 1)
    This folder contains forms for theses #5700-#5842.
- Feinstein International Center theses, 2005 -- 2012; UA098.007; 8 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains theses submitted by students for the approval of their thesis for the Masters in Humanitarian Assistance from the Feinstein International Center.
  - How Micro Level Conflicts Fuel National and Regional Wars in East Africa: A Case Study of Sudan, 2005; UA098.007.001.00001; Burns, John; On January 9th 2005 through the facilitation of the Inter Governmental Authority on Development (IGAD), the Government of Sudan (GoS) and the Sudan Peoples Liberation Movement (SPLM/A), the two main parties to North South conflict in Sudan, signed a comprehensive peace agreement purposing to end the longest running Civil War in Africa. The conflict in Sudan is multi dimensional and has operated at several different levels; this is particularly evident in the South where the Civil War landscape has been superimposed with intra regional and localized micro conflicts. These south-south conflicts may well constitute the greatest challenge to a sustainable peace in southern Sudan. This paper will examine the linkages between the different levels of conflict, and aims to present the argument that micro conflicts are not by-products of the Civil War but provide the kindling that fuels regional and national conflict, and indeed that the roots of the Civil War can be traced back to local conflicts. If this is the case it will have far reaching implications on the post conflict peace building environment, and on the IGAD peace process as a whole, which has already received criticism for not addressing regional and micro conflict at least at the political level (Sudan Mirror 2004).
    Sudan--History--Civil War, 1983-2005
  - Vulnerability in the Urban Environment: A Comparative Analysis, 2009; UA098.007.001.00002; Rae, Christopher; In 2007, the Internal Displacement Monitoring Center estimated that the total number of individuals who had been forcibly displaced from their homes, but remained within the territory of boundaries of their country, surpassed 27 million. (Jennings, 2008) Known as Internally Displaced Persons (IDPs), their numbers have been steadily growing since the early 1990s. Defined by the Guiding Principles on Internal Displacement (Guiding Principles) as persons or groups of persons who have been forced or obliged to flee or to leave their homes or places of habitual residence, in particular as a result of or in order to avoid the effects of armed conflict and who have not crossed an internationally recognized state border", IDPs have overtaken refugees as the largest constituent of forced migrants throughout the world. (Jennings, 2008; United Nation, 1998:2) But what specifically are the protection needs of the displaced? What deprivations have they suffered during their flight, and what distinguishes them from other conflict-affected populations? The purpose of this study is to better understand the experience of IDPs living in urban centers, the specific risks they face, and the means with which they mitigate those challenges. This study examines if IDPs are more vulnerable than voluntary (economic) migrants or their long-term resident neighbors, and analyzes what factors most influence vulnerability in the urban context. To compare the relative vulnerability of urban residents, the author constructed a vulnerability index oriented around risk indicators and influencing factors drawn from the survey tools used in the IDMC-Tufts urban IDP profiling study, which collected data from 3 urban centers known to host large numbers of forced migrants: Santa Marta (Colombia), Khartoum (Sudan), and Abidjan (Ivory Coast.)(Jacobsen, 2008(1); Jacobsen, 2008(2); Jacobsen, et al, 2008(3). The index was used in a 3 model regression analysis of the Tufts-IDMC study data: an initial model to test the validity of the index, followed a regression analysis for each indicator of the index, and a final analysis using a composite variable built on the six indicators of the index. Though a degree of variability was anticipated, IDPs were expected to be more vulnerable than other city residents across a range of indicators, and that factors such as time displaced, household composition, and education would have a particularly significant influence on vulnerability. The findings of this study varied considerably across each of the vulnerability indicators, as well as the influencing factors included in the index. The results did not fully support the hypothesis, in that IDPs were not consistently more vulnerable than other residents, but proved less vulnerable than other residents on a number of variables, including their access to water and steady employment. Education was found to be an important influence on vulnerability, in that a respondents level of education was strongly correlated with low vulnerability. The findings did not demonstrate a strong relation between vulnerability and the length of time of displacement, nor was it able to adequately illuminate how a households configuration influences vulnerability. This study found that vulnerability was most readily identified at the household level, rather than within a specific sub-group within the broader community, and in this regard, this study provides further support to the hypothesis that IDPs are often vulnerable, but as a group, aren't adequately homogenous to warrant preferential treatment prima facie. Rather, vulnerability in the urban context, whether experienced by IDPs, voluntary migrants, or long-time residents, must be considered at the household level, as an analysis of the risks vulnerable groups face in the city, balanced against the means and mechanisms they employ to mitigate those risks.
    Internally displaced persons --Refugees
  - A Case Study of Rural Forest Guinea, Guinea, 2009; UA098.007.001.00003; Peeters, Loek E. A.
    Food supply --Economics
  - At the Intersection of United States Policy and Humanitarian Action in Pakistan, 2010; UA098.007.001.00004; Rasmussen, Colin
    United States--Foreign relations--Pakistan
  - The Relevance of Neutrality in Humanitarian Action in the intra-state Conflicts of the 20th and 21st Century, 2012; UA098.007.001.00005; Holmberg, Daniel H.
    Submitted in partial fulfillment of the degree Master of Arts in Humanitarian Assistance at the Feinstein International Center.
    MAHA thesis; Humanitarian Assistance; Neutrality
  - Does Utilizing Immediate Crisis Intervention Tools Post Critical Incident Mitigate Short-Term Distress and or Long-Term Negative Psychological Impact on Responders in Complex Emergencies?, 2012; UA098.007.001.00006; Gould, Rose B.
    MAHA thesis; Psychological debriefing; Crisis intervention (Mental health services); Humanitarian Assistance
  - Livelihood History and Humanitarian Knowledge in Protracted Food Crisis: A Case Study of Save the Children-UK in Wollo, Ethiopia, 2012-12; UA098.007.001.00007; Gengenbach, Heidi
    Welo Kifle Hāger (Ethiopia); MAHA thesis; Food security; Humanitarian Assistance; Case studies
  - Risks and Opportunities Associated with Integration of Emergency Programs into Social Protection, 2012-04; UA098.007.001.00008; Badarch, Munkhzaya; Case study: Integration of Emergency Therapeutic Feeding Program "Community-Based Management of Acute Malnutrition" into the Health Care System in Malawi
    Malawi; MAHA thesis; Case studies; Food security